<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.4.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-08-24T15:51:14+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">WPF Digitale Kommunikation</title><subtitle>Diese Seite entstand im Rahmen des Wahlpflicht Moduls &quot;Digitale Kommunikation&quot;.
</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Introduction</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/06/02/intro.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Introduction" /><published>2017-06-02T21:03:13+02:00</published><updated>2017-06-02T21:03:13+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/06/02/intro</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/06/02/intro.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;summary&quot;&gt;Summary&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An international project was carried out as part of the „Digital communication“ event. To optimize
this , I will discuss various aspects of the event and descripe my expirience. Furthermore , the
proposals should be used to weigh up proposals for soulutions. This is, however , only the personal
experience within the project as a team member.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-project&quot;&gt;The Project&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The event was designed as a pilot project for future projects of this kind. Students from the countries
of France, Germany, Portugal, Greece and Bulgaria were to collaborate on a project collaboratively, in
mixed teams. The students should organize themselves completely independently. No tools were
provided for this. The students came from various fields, such as computer science, design and
communication. The project was started with an initial event in which all participating countries
received a briefing by videoconferencing. Afterwards, the work was carried out in the form of a multi-
page document. The task and information was written in English.
No milestones or timetables were specified. In total, the project had to be carried out about 10 days.
The challenge was to reorganize within an international team and to complete the work assignment
as successfully as possible. At the end of the event, the French participants were graded for their
achievements and had to present their own project to the customers. It was foreseen that the non-
French participants would also participate in the presentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;retrospective&quot;&gt;Retrospective&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In principle one must say that all resutls were relatively postitiv. The team was very good and there
were no problems within the team members. After a bumpy start-up phase, all the team members
had found themselves and after a while they decided to go for the Slak platform. At first we tried to
find out which team member ould do what they could to get the right tasks. In out team, there were
a total of 3 to 4 developers, 2 designers and the rest came from the marketing and communication.
In order to divide the tasks again smaller groups were formed which should act among themselves. At
first, it was clear quite quickly that the developers had almost nothing to do at the beginning, since
they had not received any work assignments yet. The project members from the marketing sector
were very busy with their campaign. However, since none of these project members had experience
in IT / project management, there were some problems. In the first step, the computer scientists
would have had to ask for, or have had to develop, requirements for the system so that they could get
a rough picture of the future architecture. It was unclear to the computer what exactly the plan of the
rest of the group was. A sidemap has been developed in the course of this process in order to
visualize which parts of the portal should exist. A sidemap made it clear which parts of the portal had
to be created, but no requirements or specifications were developed. Since it is difficult to build a
system without requirements or specifications, only one clickdummy was developed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It would have been much easier if there was a clear framework. If one knew which technology or
which components are needed, one would have had to spend much less time in the consideration
and planning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall the project was successful. Since everyone with a different motivation or a different
expectation of the project approached, one can not assume that each the same experience could
take with them. It was surprising how much you could create in an international team with different
group members. Unfortunately, there were difficulties in the planning of the project. Because each
country had a different motivation in the project, the relationship was a little unbalanced. For us from
Germany it was rather an experience, which is why we did not have the pressure like the French. I
think it would look different if the project were carried out as a full-fledged event. Alternatively, the
event could be held as an optional subject during a project week.
Since my expectations of the project were very special, I have been a little disappointed. However, I
had to realize that such a pilot project should not expect too much, just because it is not clear how
the event is taking place.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Summary An international project was carried out as part of the „Digital communication“ event. To optimize this , I will discuss various aspects of the event and descripe my expirience. Furthermore , the proposals should be used to weigh up proposals for soulutions. This is, however , only the personal experience within the project as a team member.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Project</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/06/01/the-project.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Project" /><published>2017-06-01T21:03:13+02:00</published><updated>2017-06-01T21:03:13+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/06/01/the-project</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/06/01/the-project.html">&lt;p&gt;The event was designed as a pilot project for future projects of this kind. Students from the countries
of France, Germany, Portugal, Greece and Bulgaria were to collaborate on a project collaboratively, in
mixed teams. The students should organize themselves completely independently. No tools were
provided for this. The students came from various fields, such as computer science, design and
communication. The project was started with an initial event in which all participating countries
received a briefing by videoconferencing. Afterwards, the work was carried out in the form of a multi-
page document. The task and information was written in English.
No milestones or timetables were specified. In total, the project had to be carried out about 10 days.
The challenge was to reorganize within an international team and to complete the work assignment
as successfully as possible. At the end of the event, the French participants were graded for their
achievements and had to present their own project to the customers. It was foreseen that the non-
French participants would also participate in the presentation.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The event was designed as a pilot project for future projects of this kind. Students from the countries of France, Germany, Portugal, Greece and Bulgaria were to collaborate on a project collaboratively, in mixed teams. The students should organize themselves completely independently. No tools were provided for this. The students came from various fields, such as computer science, design and communication. The project was started with an initial event in which all participating countries received a briefing by videoconferencing. Afterwards, the work was carried out in the form of a multi- page document. The task and information was written in English. No milestones or timetables were specified. In total, the project had to be carried out about 10 days. The challenge was to reorganize within an international team and to complete the work assignment as successfully as possible. At the end of the event, the French participants were graded for their achievements and had to present their own project to the customers. It was foreseen that the non- French participants would also participate in the presentation.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Concept</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/05/28/concept.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Concept" /><published>2017-05-28T21:03:13+02:00</published><updated>2017-05-28T21:03:13+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/05/28/concept</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/05/28/concept.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;introduction&quot;&gt;introduction&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After I described the project from my point of view and looked at the individual aspects which have
gone well and not so well I will now explain and weigh up an approach for future projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;project-management-methods&quot;&gt;Project management methods&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within the framework of a student project it is possible to use a modified scrum methodology. Of
course you could add a few static elements, such as fixed taxes or deadlines. It would be a great
advantage if the students were given a kind of scrum board, in which each student would be given
assignments. The tasks would then be more clearly distributed. One could also see how far a task is.
Due to the various columns in the Scrum-Board (Open, in work, Review and Finished) you would also
have less effort in assessing progress as a customer and “project manager” or product owner. This
ensures that you can recognize where any help or resources are needed. This could be helpful
especially with short projects.
But to use a scum board you need tasks or items. This actually originates before a sprint1. Since,
however, there is no real sprint and no sprint planning available to the students, in which items can
be presented by the product owner, it is a good idea. The items could be described relatively roughly,
which would mean that the teams would be able to look at these items in more detail and work out
the appropriate new items for everyone. This could happen collaboratively in the early days.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">introduction After I described the project from my point of view and looked at the individual aspects which have gone well and not so well I will now explain and weigh up an approach for future projects.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Task division</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/05/27/task-division.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Task division" /><published>2017-05-27T21:03:13+02:00</published><updated>2017-05-27T21:03:13+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/05/27/task-division</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/05/27/task-division.html">&lt;p&gt;It would make sense beforehand to consider the division of tasks. In doing so, the effort should be
compared with the goal to be achieved. Also, it is very important from the ground up to distribute the
rollers appropriately. In addition, it would be extremely useful to create an instance that controls the
progress of the project team throughout the project. In addition, a person as a product owner would
be useful. This role should, if possible, be taken over by one of the organizers since there is no real
client. In the classic Scrum, the product owner and the client must decide together what is
developed. However, since one of the two roles does not exist at all, one should reduce this and use a
sensible alternative.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;product-owner&quot;&gt;Product Owner&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Prodct Owner is actually the person who makes the requirements and carries out the acceptance
tests. However, implementation in such a small project is very impractical. The role would be useful to
provide the student with an instance that keeps the overview or controls the progress of the team.
Decrees would not have to happen as planned by the product owner, but could possibly be done by
the whole team or by responsible persons.
It would also be useful to divide the role to several students. In practice, it looks as if each of the
customers is responsible for a completed task or the entire team is classified as a customer. Thus,
several people could review the completed tasks, which would result in the project participants
having a better insight into the tasks of the others. The advantage would be early detection, where
there may be need for rework.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;system-architect&quot;&gt;System Architect&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a system architect, you should be responsible for setting up the system architecture. This includes
the choice of technology, as well as the installation and management of this technology. You should
also make the preparation for domain models for the developers. For example, database models
could already be created and discussed with the developers. These should then be introduced by the
System Architect. The System Architect could take on the role of providing developers with the right
platform. Of course, this also implies the agreement with the developers. It would be optimal if all
together the requirements from the technical side to the system and the System Architect these
implement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;developer&quot;&gt;Developer&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The developers should devote themselves exclusively to the implementation of the software.
Depending on the technology, different skills are required. It would be an advantage if all developers
were on the same level, or if they were familiar with the same technologies. In order to be able to
work as efficiently as possible, the students should be able to use CVS or Git (or GitHub) as version
control. If you use these tools effectively, you can work much more effectively collaboratively. By
creating different branches, each developer can work on their own sub-task.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;designer&quot;&gt;Designer&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The design students should create mockups and / or a CI which can then be implemented by some of
the developers. In principle one could schedule 1 to 2 days for this task. In addition, they could help
with the advertising campaign, as was currently the case in our project.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">It would make sense beforehand to consider the division of tasks. In doing so, the effort should be compared with the goal to be achieved. Also, it is very important from the ground up to distribute the rollers appropriately. In addition, it would be extremely useful to create an instance that controls the progress of the project team throughout the project. In addition, a person as a product owner would be useful. This role should, if possible, be taken over by one of the organizers since there is no real client. In the classic Scrum, the product owner and the client must decide together what is developed. However, since one of the two roles does not exist at all, one should reduce this and use a sensible alternative.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Project Requirements</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/05/26/project-requirement.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Project Requirements" /><published>2017-05-26T21:03:13+02:00</published><updated>2017-05-26T21:03:13+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/05/26/project-requirement</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/05/26/project-requirement.html">&lt;p&gt;In this section, you will find possible guidelines for the project, which could help the students to
improve the project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;project-plan&quot;&gt;Project Plan&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A rough project plan / course plan would be useful to determine when which parts of the project
should be finished. With this specification you can prevent the stagnation at a task or see the fulfilled
tasks, which are already due. Also, this serves as a reference for the students so they do not put too
much time into a themed area. The students could thereby assess their ability to test expences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;items&quot;&gt;Items&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Teachers could already develop rough tasks / items during the elaboration of the task, which the
students would have to divide again into sub-tasks. A major task at the beginning of the project could
be that the students could put together requirements for the system. This could be used to develop
use cases or user stories. These must then be implemented, for example, by the developers. By the
number of items to be done, the students would have a feeling for the effort that would still be
needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;scrum-board&quot;&gt;Scrum Board&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ScrumBoard is the tool that represents how far an item has been edited. This is mainly for the
overview of the individual tasks and the progress. In general, the ScrumBoard is divided into several
columns:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;todos--storys&quot;&gt;Todos / Storys&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are the items listed as stories, which must be implemented by the developers. This can be done
from the backlog or you can simply create new tasks. Often it is to create a story tasks, from which in
turn more can arise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;progress&quot;&gt;Progress&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are the tasks listed that should be currently handled by the project members.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;testing--review&quot;&gt;Testing / Review&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this section, completed tasks are checked by other project members and, if necessary, tested for
acceptance criteria&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;done&quot;&gt;Done&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is where the tasks are performed when they are completely revised and meet all acceptance
criteria.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A scrum board could be created digitally but also analog. There is a lot of free tools available online
for this board, which also work very well. The illustration is only an example of a scrum board. It can
be seen that the items have different colors to distinguish the type of the item. Another methodology
in Scrum would be to place a sticker or point on an item after the last day, which was in the same
state the previous day. This means that if Item 1 remains in the “Progress” area for three days, it will
receive three stickers. This allows you to see how long an item is already in the same state.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;tools&quot;&gt;Tools&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With project work hardly any tools are needed. The problem is to make the right choice. Tools should
make working on a project more efficient. Since there were participants from different locations in
our project, one should absolutely use tools that enable constant communication to be maintained. If
possible via instant messaging or in the best case via voice or video conferencing. The next section
will deal with this topic.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">In this section, you will find possible guidelines for the project, which could help the students to improve the project.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Communication</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/05/25/communication.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Communication" /><published>2017-05-25T21:03:13+02:00</published><updated>2017-05-25T21:03:13+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/05/25/communication</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/05/25/communication.html">&lt;p&gt;This section lists various ways to increase communication within the team. It should be noted that
there is a spatial separation of the team members. Since the teams come from different countries and
the communication is compulsory in English, one should assume that each participant speaks English
confidently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;skype&quot;&gt;Skype&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The well-known instant messaging tool from Microsoft can now be more than a few years ago.
However, the main functions are the exchange of messages, internet telephony and video
conferences. In addition, Skype also provides the function of screen transmission. This allows a user
to transfer their own desktop to another user (also known as TeamViewer).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;slack&quot;&gt;Slack&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slack is a web-based instant messaging service that allows a team to share files, as well as provide
different rooms to communicate with each other. Chat rooms with different topics are created for this
purpose. Users can then join the appropriate room. Slack provides the integration of various services,
such as Google Drive. Slack works natively in the browser, but can also be used as a desktop app and
as a mobile app for both common operating systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;trello&quot;&gt;Trello&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bei Trello handelt es sich um eine reine webbasierte Projektmanagementsoftware. Trello bietet die
Möglichkeit an, auf sogenannten Boards, mit anderen Mitgliedern Listen zu erstellen. Diese können
dann beliebig bearbeitet und mit Checklisten, Anhängen und mit einem festgelegten Termin versehen
werden. Neben einer mobilen Version gibt es auch passend dazu Apps für beide gängigen Plattformen
sowie Windows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;git&quot;&gt;Git&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Git is a free software for managing file diversion. It works distributed. This means that there is no
central sever, but each has its own local copy of the repository including the version history. Git is
mainly a tool for developers. Nevertheless, it is in any case one of the tools that is developed in large
projects in which software is developed. With Git, software can be better distributed. Everyone can
work on the same program. In the best case everyone gets a partial task and then independent and
independently from the other team. When someone is finished, only the part that has been edited by
the project member is added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are relatively many tools you can use for project management. However, you have to pay
attention to what you need. Depending on the project type and affinity of the project members,
different tools can be used. Since not all students are IT Affin, one could consider whether one uses
several tools for different tasks. Skype offers the possibility to see in a videoconference, what would
be important for such a project, since this can be mediated trust.
As part of the project, a continuous exchange of information must take place, which is why you
should have an instant messaging tool. Furthermore, a board as described in the section “Scrum Board”
would also be useful. Also, a central place to exchange files would be very helpful. Especially
for developers the use of Git would be very helpful.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">This section lists various ways to increase communication within the team. It should be noted that there is a spatial separation of the team members. Since the teams come from different countries and the communication is compulsory in English, one should assume that each participant speaks English confidently.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Prospect</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/05/24/prospect.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Prospect" /><published>2017-05-24T21:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2017-05-24T21:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/05/24/prospect</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/05/24/prospect.html">&lt;p&gt;On the basis of the presented results and the experience gained in the project, clear pillars for a
project of this measure can be formulated. Individual skills of the students should be considered.
There should be fixed guidelines in project management. Students probably do not have much
experience in cross-department project management. None of the participants will be able to keep
an overview of the whole project, as everyone will be responsible for their own area.
Possibly. One could use volunteer students or master students as project managers.
The tools can be predefined, but they do not. The communication came about intuitively, since,
however, the students whose work has been evaluated have shown more initiative, one should
consider possibly all students before the same situation. If each member knows that his work is being
evaluated, everyone has the same motivation at best.
Nevertheless, a Scrum Board would be very helpful for everyone. If possible, firstly develop stories
from which small workpackages can be laced. By using the Scrum Board, all participants can then see
how far the project or the partial task has been processed.
In summary, it can be said that such a project is very useful to carry out these framework conditions.
Especially for advanced students, this would be a way to test his abilities and to almost sniff real
project air. Nevertheless, the students should have a kind of guide available. The basic conditions are
important. In doing so, one should not limit itself to technologies, but should pay more attention to
the functionality or scope of the project. The division into tasks would ensure that everyone knows in
which task area he has to work.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">On the basis of the presented results and the experience gained in the project, clear pillars for a project of this measure can be formulated. Individual skills of the students should be considered. There should be fixed guidelines in project management. Students probably do not have much experience in cross-department project management. None of the participants will be able to keep an overview of the whole project, as everyone will be responsible for their own area. Possibly. One could use volunteer students or master students as project managers. The tools can be predefined, but they do not. The communication came about intuitively, since, however, the students whose work has been evaluated have shown more initiative, one should consider possibly all students before the same situation. If each member knows that his work is being evaluated, everyone has the same motivation at best. Nevertheless, a Scrum Board would be very helpful for everyone. If possible, firstly develop stories from which small workpackages can be laced. By using the Scrum Board, all participants can then see how far the project or the partial task has been processed. In summary, it can be said that such a project is very useful to carry out these framework conditions. Especially for advanced students, this would be a way to test his abilities and to almost sniff real project air. Nevertheless, the students should have a kind of guide available. The basic conditions are important. In doing so, one should not limit itself to technologies, but should pay more attention to the functionality or scope of the project. The division into tasks would ensure that everyone knows in which task area he has to work.</summary></entry></feed>